## **CURRICULUM VITAE**

Sujith N

Email: sujithnchandan1997@gmail.com
Contact number: +91-8151855158
+91-8660780757



Role: Contract

**Client: Unilever** 

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

To work in a challenging environment towards a successful career in SAP by making the best out of my abilities and interpersonal skills for contributing to long term progress and profitability of my employer organization and thus to make my own identity. I have over all 4+ years of experience in core master data MDM domain.

#### **PROFESSIONAL SYNOPSIS**

Results driven professional with a diverse skill set encompassing Product Master, Vendor Master, Material Master and MRO.

#### **Core Competencies:**

- Product Master data management.
- Vendor Master.
- MRO
- Bill of materials
- SAP Material Master.
- MDG
- Vendor Inactivation process and item creation process.

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

#### **Beckman Coulter (December 2024 to Till date)**

Designation: Coordinator (Product and Vendor Data Management).

- Vendor Master process in Oracle and ensuring adherence to quality requirements.
- Managing the Vendor management BPM and maintaining the quality documentations.
- Supporting with internal CAPA (Corrective and preventative actions).
- Handling Vendor Change Notification process and ensuring seamless implementation of Vendor proposed changes while upholding product quality and regulatory compliance.
- Conducting Vendor inactivation process and item creation process.
- Lead the creations and maintenances of item codes within SAP ECC, ensuring accuracy and alignment with organizational standards.
- Successfully created and managed material determination rules, improving accuracy in material substitutions and enhancing efficiency in procurement using SAP ECC.
- Developed and maintained material listings in SAP ECC, ensuring products are accurately categorized and easily accessible for reporting and analysis.
- Managing the end-to-end product data lifecycle, from creation to retirement, ensuring data integrity and consistency.

#### **GENPACT (September 2023 to November 2024)**

Designation: Senior Associate (Product Master Data Management).

- End to End Cordillera region master maintenance (Project initiation, Material code creation in GBPM, Maintenance and maintaining Material determination/listing)
- Lifecycle status change of finished good items, FDTC changes, plant/sales org extensions
- Processing mass creations/ modification
- Maintained configuration on Batch Management for materials at Material Level, Plant level. Master data uploads

through LSMW.

- Managing the end-to-end product data lifecycle, from creation to retirement, ensuring data integrity and consistency.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to gather and analyze product information, facilitating seamless integration into SAP ECC.
- Conducted regular audits and data quality checks to maintain high standards of accuracy in the product master data.
- Led the process of obsoleting products within SAP ECC, ensuring compliance with regulatory guidelines and accurate reporting.

## L & T Technology Services Pvt Ltd. (September 2021 to September 2023)

Designation: Engineer (Data Management). Client: Beckman Coulter

#### Project 1:

- Vendor Master process in Oracle and ensuring adherence to quality requirements.
- Managing the Vendor management BPM and maintaining the quality documentations.
- Supporting with internal CAPA (Corrective and preventative actions).
- Handling Vendor Change Notification process and ensuring seamless implementation of Vendor proposed changes while upholding product quality and regulatory compliance.
- Conducting Vendor inactivation process and item creation process.

#### **Project 2:**

- Lead the creations and maintenances of product codes within SAP ECC, ensuring accuracy and alignment with organizational standards.
- Implemented robust processes for GTIN assignment, adhering to industry standards and regulatory requirements.
- Managed end-to-end product data lifecycle, from creation to retirement, ensuring data integrity and consistency.
- Successfully created and managed material determination rules, improving accuracy in material substitutions and enhancing efficiency in procurement using SAP ECC.
- Developed and maintained material listings in SAP ECC, ensuring products are accurately categorized and easily accessible for reporting and analysis.
- Managing the end-to-end product data lifecycle, from creation to retirement, ensuring data integrity and consistency.

# H.V.T Technology Pvt Ltd. (April 2020 to September 2021) Client: Sphera Solutions Designation: Data Analyst (Master Data Management).

- Defining product Noun and Modifier with its application and use.
- Product Datasheet Sourcing, Attribute Data Creation, Product Classification.
- Usage of Data Dictionary to describe product and maintain the quality of the product.
- Duplicate parts identification, removal and attributes extraction and population.
- Capturing the data from
- manufacturing/supplier website and the catalogs provided to us or by online google research as per standard guidelines and schema.
- WEB SOURCING: Identification of web page of item either by online search or in catalog.
- DATA ENRICHMENT: Process of extracting product information like technical and business detail from Sourced information and input descriptions.
- DATA CLEANSING: Cleansing is a process of normalization of product information in a predefined convention, with removing errors or inconsistencies in how you describe attributes, units of measure and so on, Order- Noun, Modifier, Type, Size, Material, Additional Product Information.
- Strong proficiency in data manipulation, visualization reporting tool like Ms Excel and Spare finder (MDM tool).
- Maintaining the separate KPI's based on the Customers.
- Customers: Cargill Geos NA and China; British Petroleum; Bunge; Nouryon Etc.

INTERNSHIP COMPANY: Synchrotech Equipments Pvt Ltd (January 2019 to February 2019)

Subject: Manufacturing of Conveyors

- ISO 9001:2015, Supplier and Product Quality inspection training held by L&T technology services.
- Academic Internship Certificate.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- SAP ECC 6.0
- R360 Informatica
- Spare Finders (MDM Tool
- R360 Informatica
- Oracle Fusion
- SAP MDG

## **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION**

Qualification	Institute and Affiliating Board	Year
B.E - Mechanical     Engineering	Bangalore College Of Engineering and Technology Bangalore- Karnataka, India.	2015-2019
• PUC - PCMCs	Govt Pre-University College Byndoor, Karnataka, India	2015
• SSLC	M.D.E.R. School, Byndoor, Karnataka – India.	2013

### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

Father's Name : Sujith N
Mother's Name : Seetha
Nationality : Indian
Gender : Male

Date of Birth : 21-12-1997 Status : Unmarried

Languages Known : English, Hindi, Kannada

## **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the information and facts stated above are true, correct, and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Date :Yours Truly,Place:Sujith N